<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Alvis Ng</title><description>A collection of observations, thoughts, stories, and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.11</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 04:43:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>It’s 3rd week of December. Have you written your New Year Resolutions yet?</title><description>&lt;h2 id="ihaventandiamnotplanningtodoit"&gt;I haven’t, and I am not planning to do it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year this time many of us would passionately come out a list of TOBEs and TODOs — New Year Resolutions — the gist of the next 365 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extremely excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to write a blog post once a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/its-3rd-week-of-december-have-you-written-your-new-year-resolutions-yet/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8bea4d3e-32cb-4796-9d80-c38b7a3b4776</guid><category>Life Lessons</category><category>Self Improvement</category><category>Expade</category><dc:creator>Alvis Ng</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 06:53:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-6fQBqEr4b8AZ4xtphpVjAg.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id="ihaventandiamnotplanningtodoit"&gt;I haven’t, and I am not planning to do it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-6fQBqEr4b8AZ4xtphpVjAg.jpeg" alt="It’s 3rd week of December. Have you written your New Year Resolutions yet?"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year this time many of us would passionately come out a list of TOBEs and TODOs — New Year Resolutions — the gist of the next 365 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extremely excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to write a blog post once a week&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to get six-pack by going to gym&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to save $100K&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to buy a car&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to get a girlfriend&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to …&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to …&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to …&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to …&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to be …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to make it to 10. Heh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look at those fireworks, magnificent.
Look at the crowd, so happening! &lt;br&gt;
Look at the business sectors, next year will be a prosperous year. &lt;br&gt;
Look at the AR/VR predictions, next year will be a leap. &lt;br&gt;
Loot at me, NEW YEAR NEW ME!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st month, despite the overeating and hangover, you hit the gym. You write, just about anything that hit your mind, ignore the grammar, ignore the profanity, ignore the flow, your promises to yourself got published. Like you, your company just announced the NEW YEAR NEW VISION, fire burning within, excited. It has been superb!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;31st day, same shit different day. (︶︹︶)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March, same shit different month. What did I tell myself in the last December? Never mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fat belly is still around. Check the bank account, well, at least it is not empty, at least withdrawable. That because you’re still single? You started to hate the Mondays and struggle on living the weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Year Resolutions, guess it’s long gone by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NEW YEAR NEW ME, she’s laughing at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been there, trust me. That feeling, it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ifitistoofarawaydontevenbothertolookatit"&gt;If it is too far away, don’t even bother to look at it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting far-fetch objectives, they are not going to do good to you. Setting goals that you don’t need, they will break you. Time flies, but the next 365 days is unpredictable. Human fear what they don’t know. Fear is the first factor to run your motivation dry. When you’re not motivated, the wheel stop rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Enthusiasm is common. Commitment is rare. — Thomas Oppong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped writing New Year Resolution for the second year. Even it is now in December, I never bother to project what’s my 2017 going to look like. I focus on the day, 24-hours. Highlight the actionable, cut down the crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="focusjustdoit"&gt;Focus. Just do it…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laser focus on what you want in life. Articulate it, visualize it, lock it down, and move 1 step every time. Plan for every day, that’s it. Prioritize the most important task within that 24-hours, the task if you do it, it brings you closer to that person you’d want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="everyday"&gt;…everyday&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing it for the second year. In 2015, I’ve decided to start an Internet-based business. I started to learn to code, every day. HTML, CSS, and JS. Without a strong programming background, coding JavaScript was challenging. But for that vision, I move bit by bit every day, I’ve committed 3 hours every day 5–6am and 6–8pm for coding. In August 2015, I co-authored a hybrid mobile application with my friend from scratch using AngularJS 1.x and Meteor. I modularized a major backlog (expectations and use cases) to pieces on Trello and strive to check each of them every day before I go to bed. We completed that learning project in 5 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="onestepatatime"&gt;One step at a time.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to June 2016, my friend and I wanted to move on to next stage. It was the time, we had a very strong feeling. We decided to make our idea come to life. A community-powered adventure travel platform, web-based application. The old way of doing it, we broke it into pieces. We designed the entire application in Sketch. The entire visual being our vision, the ultimate objective. Moving on, we set a list of product backlog on Trello, break it down, commit and assemble every day. Sometimes things got delayed due to complexities and the level of our knowledge, but we rarely get frustrated, because we sort of hacked into a mindset of those tasks are very small. They are not some Goliaths, we don’t need to be David every day. If I can’t get it done today, I’m sure it is at least 70% done, so it will be alright by tomorrow. That awesome mindset hack, we love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Whoever wants to reach a distant goal must take small steps.” — Helmut Schmidt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking things down to pieces is extremely important in moving forward. An objective or a new year resolution may be easy to write, but most of the time it can be very heavy when comes to action. If we never make things smaller, we could have ended up in despair finger-pointing at each other. Now this is frustrating. The good thing about modularity is to bring you back to the focal point. To trick your mind that things are manageable and attainable. “Six-pack” is easy to write, but without visualization and a plan for you to move on progressively, the first day of HITT cardio can cripple you to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can skip the New Year Resolution and that’s perfectly fine. In the closing of 2016, perhaps we can ask ourselves a more important question, “Who I want to become?”. Go somewhere quiet, visualize the answer. If that’s truly what you want, lock it down, break things to pieces, and start checking them every single day. Don’t get distracted by what is not helping you to be that person. Most importantly, don’t ever stop, 0.1% is better than none. 1 step forward is better than not moving at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;……….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the way we do things and our project got your attention…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allow me to introduce you to Expade — A community-powered adventure travel platform. Our very first version is almost ready for launch. It is currently in private beta, there will be some bugs here and there which will be fixed as soon as possible. The private beta will be conducted for about 2–3 months time for feedbacks and iterations. In this period, we are open for suggestions of what should be done to make it serve you better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To stay in the loop on all our latest news, follow us on our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/expadeCom0"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/expadeCom/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://medium.com/expade"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we can't wait to hear from you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you would like to discuss something beyond what we have here, feel free to reach me through alvis@expade.com or a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alvis_bp"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Let’s Talk: Expade’s Way of Starting An Adventurous Journey</title><description>&lt;h2 id="becausethatspartoftheexcitement"&gt;Because that’s part of the excitement…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Adventure are not to be planned.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why not?”. Out of curiosity, we asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It depends on what level of planning, I’m a type of person who’s fine sleeping on the floor, and I’m prepared for uncertainties.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/3orieU9tXB6Q2Vp71u/giphy.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priceless feedback from one&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/lets-talk-expades-way-of-starting-an-adventurous-journey/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3d45c9-83dd-4b89-89f5-470498b52bad</guid><category>Expade</category><dc:creator>Alvis Ng</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 12:41:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-f_WCsQdGG_xtcHcAck2wSw.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id="becausethatspartoftheexcitement"&gt;Because that’s part of the excitement…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-f_WCsQdGG_xtcHcAck2wSw.jpeg" alt="Let’s Talk: Expade’s Way of Starting An Adventurous Journey"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Adventure are not to be planned.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why not?”. Out of curiosity, we asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It depends on what level of planning, I’m a type of person who’s fine sleeping on the floor, and I’m prepared for uncertainties.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/3orieU9tXB6Q2Vp71u/giphy.gif" alt="Let’s Talk: Expade’s Way of Starting An Adventurous Journey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priceless feedback from one of our subscribers, a couple of hours after we introduced &lt;a href="https://expade.com"&gt;expade.com&lt;/a&gt;. The response amazed us. This exactly was one of the very interesting pointers that puzzled us back in the ideation stage. How detailed should we go on helping our users to plan their adventure? Or should even do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An adventure, be it trekking, lakeside camping, or backpacking. It is expected to bring us unique, exciting, and fulfilling experience. The adventure mode has turned on, the pistons are racing, the adrenaline is rushing. The all out moment. The last thing we want to see is an itinerary, a pre-populated “plan” comes with an unordered list as such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;08:00 p.m. Group briefing&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;10:00 p.m. bla…bla…bla&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;12:30 p.m. Lunch&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;01:30 p.m. Group briefing again&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;01:50 p.m. bla…bla..bla..&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;03:30 p.m. The bus is here, go home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Ugh.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above scenario, that’s never our intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/ILmqMop0Q0xsQ/giphy.gif" alt="Let’s Talk: Expade’s Way of Starting An Adventurous Journey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="freedomtosteer"&gt;Freedom to steer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hammering on the words planning, we thought of a way. By keeping things simple while maintaining the momentum, Expade being the medium to help to kickstart a journey, make it visible to the world so whoever interested are welcome to join. The members are then given the power and freedom to discuss every detail of the adventure. From transportation to the tent color, all can be discussed and decided within the module. Once everything is in place, game on. It is never our intention to create an “adventure planning system”, we wanted to help adventurers to kickstart an adventure while maintaining the spirit of exploration, which is definitely full of uncertainties, there will never be an adventure if everything is certain and known, is there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/85VmrCIsk7mO4/giphy.gif" alt="Let’s Talk: Expade’s Way of Starting An Adventurous Journey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve proudly &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/2e9EOpH"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;, Expade is a community-powered adventure travel platform. Community being the keyword here. What this means is every adventure are made up by a group of people who would like to partake in an adventurous journey together. While people, freedom, and the adventure experience are on top of the list, we want to keep our interference to the minimum for now. Keeping our ears open for feedback and improve accordingly to best serve our fellow adventurers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our core is to take away the bad part while maintaining the good parts (unusual and exciting experience). Altogether, we want to build an adventure travel platform that is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;super simple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;super affordable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;super approachable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="comingsoon"&gt;Coming soon 🚀&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our very first version of &lt;a href="https://expade.com"&gt;Expade&lt;/a&gt; is almost ready for launch. It is currently in private beta, there will be some bugs here and there which will be fixed as soon as possible. The private beta will be conducted for about 2–3 months time for feedbacks and iterations. In this period, we are open for suggestions of what should be done to make it serve you better. You’re welcome to join our &lt;a href="https://forum.expade.com/"&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay in the loop on all our latest news, follow us on our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/expadeCom0"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/expadeCom/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://medium.com/expade"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we can't wait to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Introducing Expade: The first community-powered adventure travel platform.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://expade.com"&gt;Expade&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based application built for adventurers to venture to great places with like-minded people all around the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-1wWt9_6Ft8MSf1DTIA_hUg.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, my friend wanted to spend his precious holidays diving around one of the most stunning islands in the world, Sipadan Island which is located at&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/introducing-expade-the-first-community-powered-adventure-travel-platform/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7dadfccc-9424-40da-afc3-9af1ddbd1a77</guid><category>Expade</category><dc:creator>Alvis Ng</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 12:08:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-nAbzqXluw6CNFmY-d7Pf-g.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-nAbzqXluw6CNFmY-d7Pf-g.jpeg" alt="Introducing Expade: The first community-powered adventure travel platform."&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://expade.com"&gt;Expade&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based application built for adventurers to venture to great places with like-minded people all around the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-1wWt9_6Ft8MSf1DTIA_hUg.png" alt="Introducing Expade: The first community-powered adventure travel platform."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, my friend wanted to spend his precious holidays diving around one of the most stunning islands in the world, Sipadan Island which is located at Sabah (Borneo), Malaysia. He ended up in frustration. Unless he is happy to pay extra for single supplement charges (which is basically charges applied to divers who are not in a group) and accommodation for 2 persons (most dive resorts are based on twin sharing, there is dorm accommodation, but that’s rare), it’s a no go for him. In the end, he canceled the trip because he decided that it’s not worth it to go on a trip that costs about 50% more than the usual price for 3 days 2 nights dive trip simply because he’s a lone adventurer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-Yd_RcUlEWt2o3pRAUw-v2A.png" alt="Introducing Expade: The first community-powered adventure travel platform."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 months ago he shared this frustration to me in great length during our casual meeting. The discussion later motivated us to dig further into this particular matter. After some researches and asking around, we learned that a lot of adventurers are actually facing relatively the same problem when it comes to kickstarting similar adventurous activities. Most adventurous activities require a minimum pax, usually 4 persons, adventure tourists who traveled alone and wanted to spend their precious travel time on an adventure to some of the most beautiful wonders on earth that God has created for us, will either shell out more money than usual or canceled. &lt;br&gt;
At the same time, we also found a great length of Reddits where people looking for travel partners to partake in their journeys, but the rate of happening is disappointedly low. A lot of trips ended up postponed, change of venue or activity, or even canceled. This is not fun. We strongly felt that this problem has to be tackled, the community is in demand of a solution. While both of us are front-end and back-end developers, we thought maybe we could help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ourvision"&gt;Our vision&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we moved on to the drawing board. We collect all our thoughts and restructured them into a vision of what this very solution should ultimately achieve. We want to build &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;a community-powered adventure platform to enable everyone to adventure to anywhere with anyone in any parts of the world. It has to be Super simple. Super affordable. Super Approachable. We believe that anyone from anywhere should be able to explore the masterpiece that our mother nature has granted us to appreciate, without any cultural, racial, age, social status, or budget constraints.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="howitworks"&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Expade, we break down the flow of kickstarting a journey into 3 simple steps. Search/create → Join &amp;amp; discuss → Go there together! Super simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It has to be Super simple. Super affordable. Super Approachable……without any cultural, racial, age, social status, or budget constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following image provide a more detailed explanation: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-sNm8AThRoMxldEECz3zXdA.png" alt="Introducing Expade: The first community-powered adventure travel platform."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expade is the first community-powered adventure travel platform. Going beyond our normal known area, seeking out new and unique experiences has always been an exciting thing for the human to do. We love it. It develops us. It is life-changing, inspiring, and rewarding. But most of the time, what keeps us from doing it is because of the price to pay, the planning process, and the safety concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A platform to co-create adventurous journey with people all around the world. With no barrier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we can break these barriers? What if we can pull the cost down? What if we can shorten the process and at the same time mitigate the safety issues with the help of others? We couldn’t be more excited to be part of this mission making adventure travel to be a &lt;strong&gt;super approachable&lt;/strong&gt; subject for everyone and to open up a whole new scene in this very sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="comingsoon"&gt;Coming soon 🚀&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our very first version of &lt;a href="https://expade.com"&gt;Expade&lt;/a&gt; is almost ready for launch. It is currently in private beta, there will be some bugs here and there which will be fixed as soon as possible. The private beta will be conducted for about 2–3 months time for feedbacks and iterations. In this period, we are open for suggestions of what should be done to make it serve you better. You’re welcome to join our &lt;a href="https://forum.expade.com/"&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay in the loop on all our latest news, follow us on our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/expadeCom0"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/expadeCom/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://medium.com/expade"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we can't wait to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>The reasons why I love the 30-year-old me.</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is like riding a bicycle. To keep your balance, you must keep moving. — Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a billionaire, I don’t have a mansion, I don’t have a Ferrari, I don’t have a jet… But I’m a very RICH man, a very RICH 30-year-old&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-reasons-why-i-love-the-30-year-old-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">671aaf3f-5437-4782-88b0-16275aaa32bb</guid><category>Life Lessons</category><category>Self Improvement</category><dc:creator>Alvis Ng</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 11:49:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-Pz6m2nosRS88SnspASFEWg.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/12/1-Pz6m2nosRS88SnspASFEWg.jpeg" alt="The reasons why I love the 30-year-old me."&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life is like riding a bicycle. To keep your balance, you must keep moving. — Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a billionaire, I don’t have a mansion, I don’t have a Ferrari, I don’t have a jet… But I’m a very RICH man, a very RICH 30-year-old man, and it’s extremely joyful to be that man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id="whenisayilovemy30yearoldlifeimean"&gt;When I say I love my 30-year-old-life, I mean…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a belief; I came to believe in God in the year 2011 and my life never is same again since that day. It’s 2016 and I still holding on to the fact that If HE can transform the old me, I believe I have everything to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a laser focus; everything I am doing now is for the change I want to see next second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am extremely motivated; I wake up at 4.30 am every day to get myself closer to my life vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a lovely family; I recently learned that I can love my family more than money and career. I have a very lovely wife who loves me tirelessly, a mother and sister who always there for me when I need them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read a lot; A lot more than I have read before the entire past 30 years. 1 book in 2.5 weeks, I just love it! I just completed David and Goliath during my vacation last week, learned a lot of how to leverage what you have to achieve what you want tomorrow. What is better than becoming wiser?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I listen a lot too; I recently realize that I learned more from listening than talking. That includes listening from great people around the world. Instead of listening to latest pop, I listen to the podcast every day when I drive to work. Starting from Nothing and TEDTalks are my everyday speakers. I couldn’t be happier listening to them with JBL Flip 3 that solved my problem of not having a modern car audio system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know how to say “NO”; Unless it is a “Hell yeah! Let’s do it now!”, I would go with a big “NO”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't have FANCY clothing anymore; I only wear all dark blue or white tops every day. I am free from what-to-wear-syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t compare anymore; everyone is unique, we come from different background equipped with very different talents and possessions. We never really lack anything, everyone has enough to do what they want to do. So why compare?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t care unconstructive feedback; I remember I’ve developed a little mindset hack for myself in 2015 and it goes like this: “We tend to face challenges every day, we can’t avoid that. This applies to the people around us too, we need to expect there will be at least one asshole trying to upset you every day. So when they come, I’ll have my heart and nerves prepared and say “HERE I AM! COME AT ME BRO!”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life in the 30s is full of excitements, it is a chapter where I learn a lot of new things every day. Constantly developing strategies to utilize my 24-hour productively and try to live the best out of it. I am RICH because I no longer focusing on the material-driven lifestyle, but rather on my life experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my story. If you enjoyed this post, please do share it with the world!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>